Be afraid. Be very afraid.
The Fly is a horror, science fiction film directed by David Cronenberg.
When Seth Brundle makes a huge scientific and technological
breakthrough in teleportation, he decides to test it on himself.
Unbeknownst to him, a common housefly manages to get
inside the device and the two become one.
Seth Brundle, played by Jeff Goldblum.
Veronica Quaife, played by Geena Davis.
Stathis Borans, played by John Getz.
Tawny, played by Joy Boushel.
Dr. Cheevers, played by Leslie Carlson.
Marky, played by George Chuvalo.
The Fly is a 1986 American science fiction body horror film
directed and co-written by David Cronenberg.
Produced by Brooksfilms and distributed by 20th Century Fox, the
film stars Jeff Goldblum, Geena Davis, and John Getz.
Loosely based on George Langelaan's 1957 short story of the same name and the 1958 film of the same name, The Fly tells of an
eccentric scientist who, after one of his experiments goes wrong, slowly turns into a fly-hybrid creature.
The score was composed by Howard Shore and the make-up effects were created
by Chris Walas, along with makeup artist Stephan Dupuis.
The Fly was released on August 15, 1986, to positive reviews.
It grossed $60.6 million at the box office, becoming a commercial success.
Walas and Dupuis' work on the film resulted in them
winning an Academy Award for Best Makeup.
The tagline of the film, "Be afraid.
Be very afraid.", has been used in many other
productions as part of popular culture.
A sequel, directed by Walas, was released in 1989.
The film explores themes of monster, experiment,
mutation, toronto, canada, mutant.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.